# Obada Jasem

## Frontend Developer

Software Engineer with over 3 years of experience in frontend development for mobile and web, with a demonstrated history of building efficient and scalable applications, I have a good background in Dart, Flutter, Android and Javascript.

Dubai, United Arab Emarites

in linkedin.com/in/obada-jasm

## +971 50 914 8497

obadajasem.github.io

github.com/obadaJasm

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Frontend Developer

B&S 🗷

03/2022 - Present

Dubai, UAE

- enhancing existing features for large-scale e-commerce with multi Business domain orientations.
- Implementing unit and integration tests for different code areas through the code base.

# Frontend Developer

Nestech 🗷

09/2021 - 03/2022

Syria (Remote)

- Converted design into high-class frontend web applications with the help of the quasar framework.
- Engaged in daily scrum meetings with our 5 members' team to optimize the development process.
- Worked on internal company mobile applications using flutter framework.
- Saved 20% of company time in creating a single module unit by writing boilerplate code to initiate the module structure by scripting the process using is and node.js.

# **Mobile Application Developer**

Badinan Soft 2 12/2020 - 09/2021

Iraq (Remote)

- Implemented high-quality mobile applications with flutter and native android java for company-existed order system.
- Created a TV-oriented design video stream android native app using leanback library.
- Created company-base-package to reuse shared logic and style across different apps to gain more control and flexibility and reduce multi-file changes if needed.

# Mobile Application Developer

**Qlevar** 

07/2020 - 08/2021

Germany (Remote)

- Implemented and updated application modules under the direction of Senior Software Engineer.
- Efficiently translated client requirements into application designs and system requirements.

# **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Informatics Engineering Department of Software Engineering

Tishreen Unviersity

06/2016 - 06/2021

# **SKILLS**



## PERSONAL PROJECTS

### TasOment 🗹

- Transformed the design of the application into a well-structured mobile application.
- Implemented SSO, 2FA, and chat system in the project.
- Upload the Mobile app to google play as a test release.
- Stack: Vue.js, Element UI, Vuex, SortableJS, PHP, Laravel, Dart, Flutter, Firebase, Pusher.

#### Qlevar 🗹

- led the process of converting the design into actual codebase using flutter framework in web base platform.
- attended the scrum meetings with product owner to convert the spoken language into user stories.
- Implemented a real-time server communication connection using signalR between the dashboard and the user app.
- Stack: Flutter, Dart, Provider, Getx, Asp.net, Signal R.

#### INTV+

- Implement TV-oriented design for android mobile application using leanback library.
- Stack: Java, leanback library, Firebase.

#### Badinan Shipping 🗹

- Implemented local package to help other apps which depends on it to easily access shared logic and company theme.
- translated the system structure decisions and contributed to the modular structure used in the application.
- Created a node server using Express JS to track the driver location using Socket IO and integrating it with the mobile flutter app.
- Stack: Flutter, Dart, Laravel, Express, Node.js, Firebase, Lifecycle:extensions.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### Won 3rd place in Tamayuz competition

Participated in the "Encouraging Arabic content to use digital transformation tools" category.

# **LANGUAGES**

Arabic Native or Bilingual Proficiency English

Full Professional Proficiency